Michael Beltz

Experienced IT Manager dedicated to delivering results.

Lincoln, NE - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Michael-Beltz/0a9c099d1f8e31d6

I am a IT leader with 17 years of experience managing and participating in high profile large scale IT projects. A highly motivated leader who understands how to get the best out of associates by developing talents and focusing on empowerment. I have a history of achieving business results thru structured IT principals and high levels of communication throughout the business as well as within the IT organization.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manager Cloud Operations

Upland Software - Lincoln, NE - January 2017 to Present

The Manager of Cloud Operations is responsible public and private cloud infrastructure and application production support across all Upland Software product lines. The cloud operations team is globally diversified team that supports multiple application platforms serving multiple industries focusing on workflow automation, IT and Project Management and mobile engagement.

Director of IT Operations

NATIONAL RESEARCH CORPORATION - March 2014 to December 2016

The Director of IT Operations is in charge of all systems, networks, databases, and service desk incidents that effect internal and external clients. Primary responsibilities include maintaining high performing systems across all data centers and office locations as well utilizing innovative problem solving to create solutions as technology evolves to best serve our clients.

Other duties include managing Microsoft license EA agreement, purchasing of equipment, digital security enforcement and ITIL education and best practices.

Systems Engineering Manager

NATIONAL RESEARCH CORPORATION - February 2012 to February 2014

Team manager of a globally located group of system engineers and database administrators. Responsible for stability, reliability and performance of NRC systems across multiple platforms in all locations.

Senior Enterprise Database Administrator

NATIONAL RESEARCH CORPORATION - July 2007 to March 2012

DBA in charge of database and network backup strategy and SAN management using a mixture of Dell Equallogic, EMC and openfiler storage. Perform a range of database functions including server upgrade and maintenance, strategic growth and capacity planning and performance tuning on all systems within our network. Responsible for over 35 SQL servers hosting over 100 databases.

Consultant

AMERITAS LIFE INSURANCE CORP - December 1999 to July 2007

Lead programmer and Database administrator for Group Dental and Vision Sales engine via n-tier web application.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Information Systems Management

Doane College-Lincoln Grand Island and Master 2006 to 2011

Associate in Applied Science, Computer Programming

Southeast Community College - Milford, NE 1998 to 1999

Master's in Business Administration

Nebraska Wesleyan University January 2016

SKILLS

Leadership (3 years), IT Management (5 years), It Project Management (5 years), Database Management (8 years)

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

March 2012

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Specialties: ● Information Technology and Network Services ● Technical Architecture and Design ● Employee Training, Development and Coaching ● International Team Management ● Strategic and Business Planning ● Vendor Relationship Management ● Financial Management ● IT Acquisition management and tasking